Just 10 seconds . . . to save a dream from becoming a nuclear nightmare.
Earth II is a tv movie, science fiction film directed by Tom Gries.
In the near future, a space station dubbed Earth II is built for
the purpose of scientific research and world peace.
However, that peace is shattered when the Chinese send up a nuclear bomb
that is orbiting just a few miles away from the station.
Can the crew disarm the bomb before it detonates, not only
destroying the station but setting off World War III?
David Seville, played by Gary Lockwood.
Jim Capa, played by Scott Hylands.
Dr. Loren Huxley, played by Hari Rhodes.
Frank Karger, played by Anthony Franciosa.
Lisa Karger, played by Mariette Hartley.
Walter Dietrich, played by Gary Merrill.
Earth II is a 1971 pilot, aired November 28 (and released theatrically outside North America),
for a television series about a colony established in orbit around the Earth.
A WABE Production in association with Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Television, it
starred Gary Lockwood, Scott Hylands and Hari Rhodes.
The film was written and produced by William Read Woodfield
and Allan Balter, and directed by Tom Gries.
The film explores themes of space colony, space station,
nuclear threat, spacewalk, space walk.
The tone is thought_provoking.